Matthew Cullen

Rochester, New York, 14526 | 585-831-0531 | m23.cullen@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

Full Stack Web Developer

Experienced software designer with quality assurance and supervisory experience. Possesses strong leadership and team-building skills. Serves as a team leader to manage problem solving issues on a weekly basis. Quick learner, collaborative and creative. Works well under pressure and adapts to new concepts. Strives to write simple efficient code and contribute to the developer community.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby | Rails | SQL | Javascript | React | Django | Redux | Python | HTML | css | Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Pet-Assistant Frontend Backend | Demo

Keep track of important dates and notes for all your pets

- Used React as the frontend framework to create a single page application
- Used Redux to handle state between multiple components
- Used css and javascript to create a responsive navigation bar and layout

Fortune Teller api/client Frontend Backend | Demo

Ask a question and let the cards answer for you with multiple tarot spread options

- Created a rails api backend with Postgresql to handle CRUD/DataBase
- Created a javascript front end to connect to the api
- Used bootstrap to create a simple UI design

Book Review App Ruby on Rails - Github | Demo

Signup or login with google to read, write and comment on book reviews.

- Used rails for CRUD actions and to connect to a sglite3 database
- Created a login system that allows new users to sign up with the site or login with a google account.
- Used embedded Ruby to render views with data from the controllers

Virtual Bookcase with Sinatra - Github | Demo

Organize and keep track of your books with this virtual bookcase

- Used Ruby with the Sinatra framework and object oriented programming
- Created a login system
- Implemented proper MVC structure

EXPERIENCE

Sandwich Maker, Bruegger's Bagels, Webster, New York

06/ 2019 - Present

Make an assortment of food to the customers and Bruegger's standards

Engage customers in a friendly manner to meet all their needs

Quality assurance/supervisor, Harbec, Ontario, New York

06/2011 - 02/2015

Worked as a team to communicate problems and ensure the correct changes were made.

Supervised a team of machine operators and parts runners

Used measurement tools to determine the quality of various parts.

Groundskeeper, St. Ann's, Rochester, New York

07/ 2008 - 06/201

Responsible for the care and maintenance of the grounds and equipment

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 09/ 2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program